Guide to the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 142 Records, 1957-1995 AIS.2003.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 142 Records
1957-1995
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 142 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.2003.09
8.75 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
Robert Argentine was a construction worker and member of Local 142 of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America in Pittsburgh, Pa., and served at the top level of the Carpenters District Council of Western Pennsylvania. This collection contains meeting minutes and financial documents of Local 142 and the Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania, as well as other papers accumulated by Argentine.
Access Restrictions
Folders 1 and 45 in Box 4 are restricted for 75 years from date of creation. A signed confidentiality agreement must be signed to view the contents of these folders until the restriction is lifted. Please contact the Archives Service Center for more information.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peter Argentine in 2003.
Biography
Robert Argentine began in 1942 as a construction worker and member of Local 142 of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, which was chartered in February 1886, and represents carpenters in Pittsburgh, Pa. He later became a business agent within Pittsburgh's sub-district of the carpenters union before being elected secretary-treasurer of the Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania, the council's highest post. He also served as vice-president of the Allegheny County Labor Council, AFL-CIO. Argentine also served in several civic leadership positions, including the board of directors for the Port Authority of Allegheny County and the state planning commission under Governor Robert Casey. He died March 10, 2006.
Previous Citation
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 142 Records, 1957-1995, AIS.2003.09, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Western Pennsylvania Regional District Council of Carpenters Records, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1887-1975, AIS.1996.12, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Projects of the Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Record Books, 1938-1939, AIS.1969.19, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 430 and 165 Records, 1961-1996, AIS.1997.06, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains meeting minutes and financial documents of Local 142 and the Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania which were accumulated by Robert Argentine. Also present are contracts and by-laws from various carpenter and trade local unions and district councils. Information about the Carpenters' benefits plans and investments are also included.
Clippings (Information artifacts); Photographs; Labor; Contracts; Memorabilia; Correspondence; Minutes (Administrative records); Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Carpenters -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Carpenters -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- History; Argentine, Robert P.; Carpenters District Council of Western Pennsylvania; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 142 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Local 142 Meeting Minutes, 1958-June 1988 (Box 1, Volume 1-4)
- William J. Kelly Photographs and Clippings (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Local 142 Executive Board Minutes, 1963-1982 (Box 2, Volume 1-2)
- Proceedings of the Special General Convention of the Brotherhood of Carpenters, September 30, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Proceedings of the 31st General Convention of the Brotherhood of Carpenters, August 24-28, 1970 (Box 2, Volume 3-4)
- Contracts between Carpenters' District Council of Western PA and Master Builders' Association, 1964-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Independent Contracts of Carpenters' District Council of Western PA, 1970-1973, 1982-1985, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Contract between Carpenters' District Council of Western PA and Keystone Building Contractors' Association, Inc., 1972-1975, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Local Contracts, 1960, 1966-1968, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Agreements of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters, 1966-1968, 1971, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Other Trade Union Contracts, 1945, 1967-1977, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Jurisdictional Dispute Books, 1961-1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Constitution and By-laws, 1961-1963, 1979, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Local 142 Constitution and By-laws, 1939, 1959, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Other Carpenters Local Union By-laws (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Constitution and By-laws of Pittsburgh Area Councils, 1954, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Constitution and By-laws of Pennsylvania State Councils, 1914, 1960s, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Constitution and By-laws of Carpenters' District Council of Western PA, 1969, 1979, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- List of Union Shops Granted Use of the Union Label, 1962, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Carpenters Pension Agreements (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Carpenter and Trades Council Directories, 1970, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Union Officer Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Carpenter's Belt Buckle (Box 3, Item 1)
- Carpenters District Council of Western Pennsylvania Hats (Box 3, Item 2-4)
- Pennsylvania State Council of Carpenters Hat (Box 3, Item 5)
- Carpenters Local Union 1419 Hat (Box 3, Item 6)
- Buy American. Buy Union T-Shirt (Box 3, Item 7)
- Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania T-Shirt (Box 3, Item 8)
- Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Hardhat (Box 3, Item 9)
- Affiliation of Local 33-L with Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Draft Agreement with Master Interior Contractors' Association, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
- Local 33-L Agreements (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Rough Draft Copies of Lathers Agreement (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Membership Applications [RESTRICTED], 1971-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Labor Organization Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Local 142 Financial Statements, June 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Argentine Personal File (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Government Forms Completed by Local 142, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with Accountants, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Bonds, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Amendment to By-laws, 1957, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Local 142 Report on Examination of Accounts, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
- Local 142 Financial Statements, June 1963-June 1965 (Box 4, Folder 12-15)
- Local 142 Financial Statements, June 1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Bob Argentine Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Local 142 Financial Statements, June 1966 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Local 142 Financial Statements, June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
- Local 142 Financial Statements, June 1967-June 1975 (Box 4, Folder 21-30)
- Local 142 Financial Statements, June 1977-June 1979 (Box 4, Folder 31-34)
- Government Forms Completed by Local 142, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Financial Secretary Expenses (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Heavy Construction Problems (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Local 142 History (Box 4, Folder 38)
- International Procedural Rules and Directives, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- International Maintenance (Box 4, Folder 40)
- International Pension Reciprocity Agreement (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Payroll Sheets (Box 4, Folder 42)
- State Council of Carpenters (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Receipts (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Sick and Relief Statements [RESTRICTED] (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Local 142 Financial Papers (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Legislative and Politics, 1980, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Conventions, 1980, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Negotiations (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Carpenters' District Council Picnic (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Mail from the International Office (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Minutes (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Local 142 Contesting District Council By-laws, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Petition for Executive Action on Steel Imports (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Greater Pittsburgh Guild for the Blind, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Letter from Amalgamated Transit Workers Local 85 to Argentine, PAT Board Member, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Headquarters Building Plaque (Box 5, Item 1)
- Robert Argentine Name Plate (Box 5, Item 2)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Financial Meeting, May 17, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Second Report of the Financial Oversight Committee, August 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Financial Reviews and Reports, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Labor Organization Annual Report, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Account Summary, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Carpenters' District Council Report on Audits of Financial Statements, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Financial Statements and Report of Independent Auditors, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Carpenters' District Council Statement of Transactions, November 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Financial Documents (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Millwright-Iron Worker Rigging Disputes, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Prefabricated Modular Industry (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Agreements, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Agreement between USWA and the Building and Construction Trades Dept., 1977, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Workers Compensation Plan, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Statistics and Reports, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Carpenters District Council Overtime or Shift Permit (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Addendum to Allegheny County Sanitation Authority Contract Documents, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Election Watcher Credentials, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Carpenters Medical Plan (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Real Estate Asset Summary, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Trustees of the Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Savings and Annuity Plan, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Carpenters of Western Pennsylvania Medical Plan Investment Appraisal, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Carpenters of Western Pennsylvania Savings and Annuity Investment Appraisal, September 1993 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Carpenters of Western Pennsylvania Pension Plan Investment Appraisal, September and December 1993 (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
- Carpenters' Pension Fund of Western Pennsylvania, Actuarial Valuation, January-July 1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Carpenters' Pension Fund of Western Pennsylvania, Executive Summary, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Pension Defined Contributions, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Argentine Election Materials (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Delegate Badges (Box 6, Folder 2)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Items (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Argentine Dues Books, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- William Kelly Photographs (Box 6, Folder 5)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Conventions (Box 6, Folder 6)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Local Banquet Programs (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Apprenticeship Awards, 1974, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Banquet Programs (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Allegheny County Labor Council (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Allegheny County Labor Council, Scholarship Banquet, 1963, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Port Authority of Allegheny County, 1981, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Jurisdiction of Carpenters' District Council of Western PA, Building Trades Carpenters, and Local 2274 Heavy Construction Carpenters, March 15, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Legal Cases, 1993, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Pension Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Member Locals Information (Box 6, Volume 1)
- Carpenters of Western Pennsylvania Benefit Handbook (Box 6, Volume 2-3)
- Argentine Day Planners, 1986, 1989, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Volume 4-8)
- Franchard Corporation Stocks, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Local By-laws, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Executive Committee Report on the Resolution regarding Local 2274, March 1, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Prevailing Minimum Wage Predetermination, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Meeting Minutes, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 5-10)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters Directory, 1967 (Box 7, Volume 1)
- Modern Carpentry by Willis H. Wagner, 1974 (Box 7, Volume 2)
- The US Department of Labor Bicentennial History of the American Worker, 1976 (Box 7, Volume 3)